Children do not ask to be born, and each deserves an opportunity to thrive.
I would argue that caring and concerned adults, that includes you, have an obligation to support the learning and development of all children, heavy on all, underscore, bold, italicized.
If you do nothing else this Pride Month, identify ways that you, yes, you, can recognize, respect, and protect the rights of all young people, especially those most likely to be targeted, tormented, and terrorized.
Consider the following three things as you build your capacity toolbox.
First, words matter.
Ask the young people around you how they want to be respected.
Beyond pronouns which are important to respect, ask the following.
How do you want me to acknowledge you today?
How do you want me to acknowledge you in front of your peers?
And if you aren't their parents, ask, how do you want me to acknowledge you in front of your parents?
Two, protect peace.
While we can't mandate or legislate tolerance or acceptance, we can pass policies and inform practices prohibiting discrimination and promoting inclusive communities.
Title IX is the federal law designed to prevent discrimination on the basis of sex, and codification of the Equality Act will make explicit protections on the basis of sexual identity or sexual orientation, gender identity, and expression.
You should call your representatives at 202-224-3121 and urge support for the Equality Act today.
And then three, take a cue from Aunt Aretha who underscores the importance of respect.
Do something to support the young people you know in making sense of the world around them.
Look up the history of drag and trace it through time and space.
Learn about the life and legacy of Black queer superheroes like Marsha Payin' No Mind Johnson, Brother Bayard Rustin, Malcolm Kenyatta, and Angelica Ross.
Visit MBJC's Been Here Digital Archive for more.
And ask for help.
You're not supposed to know everything, and you should find comfort in disabusing yourself of that fallacy.
You cannot know everything.
Ask for help.
There are hundreds of us living and laboring and loving so that you can find strategies to advocate and exist as a safe space for others.
Whatever you do, do something to support the babies.
Happy Pride.